Guide to the Mario Ancona Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
- Portfolios
  - Four photographs: Eldee, Lilian; Nordica, Lillian, 1857-1914; Farneti, Maria, 1878-1955; Eames, Emma, 1865-1952 1899; 1891 (?) (Oversize 14, Folder 14)
  - Two photographs: Neilson, Julia, b. 1868; Elliott, Maxine, 1868-1940 (Oversize 14, Folder 15)
  - Four photographs: illegible name; Glasu, Lulu; Nethersole, Olga, 1870-1951; Glasu, Lulu (Oversize 14, Folder 16)
  - Two photographs: Monteith, Florence (Oversize 14, Folder 17)
  - Five photographs: Stern, Adaina; Risler, Greta; Sanderson, Lili; Hill Lucile (Oversize 14, Folder 18)
  - Three photographs: Brema, Marie; Anderson, Leona; Carlyon, Nita (Oversize 14, Folder 19)
  - Five photographs: Stagno Bellincioni, Bianca, 1888-; Farneti, Maria, 1878-1955; Pezzati, Renata; Farneti, Maria, 1878-1955; Tetrazzini Campanini, Eva (Oversize 14, Folder 20)
  - Five photographs: Reid, Margaret; Beeth, Lola; illegible names (Oversize 14, Folder 21)
  - Four photographs: Monti Baldini, Irma; Ferrani, Cesira, 1863-1943; Guerrini, Olimpia; Trisolini Repetto, Elvira (Oversize 14, Folder 22)
  - Three photographs: Bianchini Cappelli, Elena; Wagner, Alfonsina; Barrientos, Maria, 1883-1946. (Oversize 14, Folder 23)
  - Six photographs: Heller, Mira; Hirsch, Ester; Clark, Hilda; Guilbert, Ivette; Aubrey, Lilly (Oversize 14, Folder 24)
  - Six photographs: Chotkowska, Ladislas; Krusceniski, Salomea, 1872-1952; Bogescko, Marie (sp?); illegible names; Shakosky, Febea (Oversize 14, Folder 25)
  - Two photographs: De Cisneros, Eleonora; Pacini, Regina, 1871-1965 (Oversize 14, Folder 26)
  - Two photographs: Mazzoleni, Ester, 1883-1982; D'Alvarez, Marguerite, 1886-1953 (Oversize 14, Folder 27)
  - Four photographs: Giachetti, Rina; Baldisseri, Nerina; Nethersole, Olga, 1870-1951; von Reibnitz, Lily (Oversize 14, Folder 28)
  - Two photographs: Darcl#&233;e, Hariclea, 1860-1939; Farrar, Geraldine, 1882-1967 (Oversize 14, Folder 29)
  - Two photographs: Beriza, Margherita; Cavalieri, Lina, 1874-1944 (Oversize 14, Folder 30)
  - Five photographs: Arimondi, Antonio; Ercolani, Remo; Broglio, Luigi; Cima, Giuseppe; Arimondi, Vittorio, 1861-1928 (Oversize 14, Folder 31)
  - Four photographs: Tamagno, Francesco, 1850-1905; Stagno, Roberto, 1848-1897; De Lucia, Fernando, 1860-1925 (Oversize 14, Folder 32)
  - Three photographs: Maurel, Victor, 1848-1923 (Oversize 14, Folder 33)
  - Two photographs: Maurel, Victor, 1848-1923 (Oversize 14, Folder 34)
  - Four photographs: De Reszke, Edouard, 1853-1917; De Reszke, Jean, 1850-1925 (Oversize 14, Folder 35)
  - Five photographs: Lubert, Albert; De Reszke, Edouard, 1853-1917; Alvarez, Albert, 1861-1933 (Oversize 14, Folder 36)
  - Two photographs: Daubigné, Tom; Plançon, Pol, 1854-1914 (Oversize 14, Folder 37)
  - Two photographs: Cremonini, Giuseppe (Oversize 14, Folder 38)
  - Five photographs: Clay Barnaber, Henry; Guardabassi, Mario; La Puma, Giuseppe; Novacchi, Ottavio; Farka, Maurice, 1867-1916 (Oversize 14, Folder 39)
  - Four photographs: Caruso, Enrico, 1873-1921; Schipa, Tito, 1889-1965; Anselmi, Giuseppe, 1876-1929 (Oversize 14, Folder 40)
  - Two photographs: Vanni-Marcoux, 1877-1962; Dalmors, Charles, 1871-1939 (Oversize 14, Folder 41)
  - Two photographs: Dalmors, Charles, 1871-1939 (Oversize 14, Folder 42)
  - Two photographs: Vignas, Francesco, 1863-1933; Muratore, Lucien, 1878-1954 (Oversize 14, Folder 43)
  - Two photographs. Group; Isabella di Borbone, Countess of Girgenti (Oversize 15, Folder 1)
    With dedicationsIn the group:Tittoni Bice, Sonia; Traverso, Antonia; Ancona, Mario; S.A.R. la Duchessa; Aosta, Letizia di; Tormasa-Tittoni, S.E. (sp)
  - One photograph:Carlos de Branganca, King of Portugal1898 (Oversize 15, Folder 2)
  - Two photographs: Amélie de Braganca, Queen of Portugal; Luiz de Braganca, heir to the throne of Portugal (Oversize 15, Folder 3)
  - Two photographs: Manuel de Braganca, the last King of Portugal; Manuel de Besa, Duke (Oversize 15, Folder 4)
  - Three photographs: Luigi di Savoia, Duke of the Abruzzi; Victoria Melita, Grand Duchess of Russia; Letizia di Savoia Napoleone, Duchess of Aosta (Oversize 15, Folder 5)
  - Two photographs: Louis Philippe Robert, Duke of Orléans (Oversize 15, Folder 6)
  - Two photographs: Keil, Alfredo, 1850-1907; Tosti, F. Paolo (Francesco Paolo), 1846-1916 (Oversize 15, Folder 7)
  - Three photographs: Rotoli, Augusto, 1847-1904 (Oversize 15, Folder 8)
  - Four photographs: Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924 (Oversize 15, Folder 9)
  - Three photographs: Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912; D' Hardelot, Guy; Chaminade, C#&233;cile, 1857-1944 (Oversize 15, Folder 10)
  - Three photographs: Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900; Ronald, Landon, Sir, 1873-1938; Barthelemy, Richard (Oversize 15, Folder 11)
  - Two photographs: Campanini, Cleofonte; group photograph: Bevignani, Enrico Modesto, 1841-1903; Randegger, Alberto, 1832-1911; Mancinelli, Luigi, 1848-1921. (Oversize 15, Folder 12)
  - Two photographs: Mancinelli, Luigi, 1848-1921 (Oversize 15, Folder 13)
  - Six photographs: Mancinelli, Luigi, 1848-1921; Bimboni, Alberto, 1882-1960; Seidl, Anton, 1850-1898; Cumini, ?; Marinuzzi, Gino; Campanini, Cleofonte (Oversize 15, Folder 14)
  - Three photographs: Di Lorenzo, Tina, 1872-1930; Leigheb, Teresina; Leigheb, Claudio, 1848-1903 (Oversize 15, Folder 15)
  - Three photographs: Coquelin, Constant, 1841-1909; Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905; Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923 (Oversize 15, Folder 16)
  - Two photographs: R#&233;jane, 1856-1920 (Oversize 15, Folder 17)
  - Five photographs: Marteau, Henry; Wolf, Johannes, 1869-1947; Ciompi, Giorgio; Huberman, Bronislaw; Holman, Joseph (Oversize 15, Folder 18)
  - Five photographs: Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919; Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 (Oversize 15, Folder 19)
  - Two photographs: Ysae, Eugne, 1858-1931; Pugno, Raoul, 1852-1914. (Oversize 15, Folder 20)
  - Two photographs: Greco, Agesilao; Pini, Eugenio (Oversize 15, Folder 21)
  - Three photographs: Mazzantini, Luis, 1856-1936 (Oversize 15, Folder 22)
  - Two photographs: Ceccherini, Sante; Colautti, Arturo, 1851-1913 (Oversize 15, Folder 23)
  - Two photographs: Rothschild, Alfred Charles de; Grey, Gladys de (Oversize 15, Folder 24)
  - Two photographs: Woog, Raymond; Pinheiro, M. Gustavo Bordallo (Manoel Gustavo Bordallo) (Oversize 15, Folder 25)
  - Two photographs: Corcos, Vittorio, 1859-1933 (Oversize 15, Folder 26)
  - One photograph: Lessona, Carlo, 1863-1919. (Oversize 15, Folder 27)
  - Four photographs: Cornaglia, E.; Carrre, Jean, b. 1868; Massue, Nicholas; Wood, Helen (Oversize 15, Folder 28)
  - Three photographs: Hemphill, Melvin; Haupt, ?; Vannucci, ? (Oversize 15, Folder 29)
  - Two photographs: D' Ornelli, Vittoria; Hobart, Julia (Oversize 15, Folder 30)
  - Seven photographs: Toshiho, Sehiya (Oversize 15, Folder 31)
  - Nine Photographs: In opera roles. (Oversize 13, Folder 29)
    Melba, Nellie, Dame, 1861-1931; Ancona, Mario; De Lucia, Fernando, 1860-1925
- Mementos
  - Florence, School of Medicine: medical doctor degree conferred to Moisé Vita Ancona di Raffaello April 26, 1792 (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
  - Rome, nominating Giacomo Ancona Knight of the Order of the Crown of Italy; Turin, nominating, Giacomo Ancona Commander of the Order of the Crown of ItalyNov. 29, 1872; Oct. 2, 1877 (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
  - From the Tunis Kingdom Giacomo Ancona is nominated Commander of the Order of Niscian Iftikhar; Florence, the State Ministry nominates Giacomo Ancona Knight of the Order of Saints Maurizio and LazzaroMarch 18, 1871; Feb. 7, 1868 (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
  - From the University of Pisa, medical doctor degree conferred to Giacomo AnconaJune 3, 1883 (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
  - Livorno, Dr. Giacomo Ancona is nominated member of L'Accademia Labronica Nov. 9, 1852 (Oversize 8, Folder 5)
  - Florence, Institute of Higher Education: medical doctor degree conferred to Giacomo AnconaDec. 9, 1912 (Oversize 8, Folder 6)
  - Pisa University, law degree conferred to Raoul AnconaMarch 27, 1915 (Oversize 8, Folder 7)
  - Rome, War Ministry documents (two) in honor of silver medals conferred to Raoul AnconaMarch 10, 1917; Nov. 18, 1916 (Oversize 8, Folder 8)
  - Rome, War Ministry document in memory of the Lieutenant Raoul AnconaJuly 24, 1922 (Oversize 8, Folder 9)
  - Document and Etching by Max Pollack in memory of Monroe Emanuel DeutschOct. 21, 1955 (death date) (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
  - Etching by Max Pollack of Judge M. C. Sloss (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
  - Giacomo Ancona is nominated member of the Malta Medical Society Sept. 12, 1849 (Oversize 8, Folder 10)
- Opera Materials
  - New York. Metropolitan Opera House. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Nozze di Figaro Jan. 31, 1883 (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
  - London. Windsor Castle. Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Amico Fritz July, 15, 1893 (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
  - London. Royal Opera, Covent Garden. Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Rom#&233;o et Juliette July 4, 1893 (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
  - Faenza. Teatro Comunale. Windsor Castle. Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Amico Fritz Dec. 1, 1894 (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
  - New York. Metropolitan Opera House. Gala NightFeb. 15, 1894 (Oversize 8, Folder 5)
  - London. Royal Opera, Covent Garden1896 (Oversize 8, Folder 6)
  - London. Royal Opera, Covent Garden1896 (Oversize 8, Folder 7)
  - London. Royal Opera, Covent Garden1897 (Oversize 8, Folder 8)
  - London. 45 Pont Street, SW. ConcertJuly 3, 1898 (Oversize 8, Folder 9)
  - London. Windsor Castle, Royal Opera House. Adam, Adolphe, 1803-1856. Chalet; Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci July 4, 1899 (Oversize 8, Folder 10)
  - London. Royal Opera, Covent Garden1899 (Oversize 8, Folder 11)
  - London. Royal Opera, Covent Garden1899 (Oversize 8, Folder 12)
  - London. Royal Opera, Covent Garden1901 (Oversize 8, Folder 13)
  - London. Royal Opera, Covent Garden1908 (Oversize 8, Folder 14)
  - The Madison Square Garden Concert Hall. A concert and tea.Feb.11, 1895 (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
  - The Foreign Press Association Benevolent Fund. St. James Theater.June 27, 1905 (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
  - Paris. Festival MozartMarch, 1906 (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
  - Paris. Savoy Hotel. Grand ConcertJan. 24, 1911 (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
  - Jardins de l' ambassade d' Italie. Fete de Charite May 30, 1914 (Oversize 8, Folder 5)
  - Libretto. Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci (Oversize 8, Folder 6)
  - Theater contracts from 1890-1913 (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
  - Teatro de S. Carlos and Teatro Colón (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
- Publications
  - La grande stagione lirica primaverile del 1913March 1913 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Strand Musical MagazineJuly, 1897 (Othertype 9, Folder 1)
  - Strand Musical MagazineSept. 1897 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Mustraçao PortuguezaMarch 29, 1909 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Libvrni Civitas. Rassegna di attività municipale a cura del comune di Livorno1929 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Bonaventura, Arnaldo. Musicisti Livornesi1930 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Shaw on Music1955 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Musica d' oggi. Ressegna di vita e di cultura musicale. Dec. 10, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Opera NewsJanuary 18, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Opera NewsDec. 9, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hobbies. The magazine for collectorsOct. 1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hurst, P. G. Age of Jean de Reszke1958 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Opera News, Dec.31, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Opera NewsDec.8, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper clipping. La Tribuna: Il Tannhäuser al CostanziApril 11, 1900 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper clipping. La Tribuna: La terza giornata di GuglielmoMay 5, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Acknowledgements
  - Documents of Appreciation 1890-1901; Letters 1891-1911 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Arrangement of Documents by Giacomo Ancona
- Discographies
  - Record Collector. July 1964 - July 1974 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Discography created by Giacomo Ancona, Binder in handmade casing (white and red) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Discography created by Giacomo Ancona, Binder in handmade casing (white and red) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Discography created by Giacomo Ancona, Two binders in one handmade casing (white and green) (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Scores
  - Bound scores with dedications and autographs, Bound, hard covers, green with leather spine and corners. 14 1/2" by 11" (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Allisten, Frances. Chant de Grace. (New York: Boosey & Co.); Unto thy heart (London: E. Ascherberg & Co.) -- Bimboni, Alberto, 1882-1960. Serenata. (manuscript) -- Baldacci, Giovanna Bruna. Alba. (Padua: G. Zanibon) -- Barthelemy, Richard. Coeur Fidele. (Monte Carlo: D. Philippi); Délicieusement (manuscript); Je t' aime. (manuscript); Je t' aime. (Paris: G. Gross); Serenamenthe. (Paris: G. Gross); Sulla Bocca Amorosa. (Paris: G. Gross) -- Bemberg, H. (Herman), 1859-1931. Memoria. (Paris: L. Gregh) -- Billi, Vincenzo, 1869-1938. Canto Notturno. Melodia (Milano: G. Ricordi & Co.); Un Ramo di Rosa (Milano: G. Ricordi & Co.) -- Bimboni, Alberto. Romanza (manuscript); Notte serena (manuscript); Only a rose (New York: G. Ricordi & Co. c1912) -- Bimboni, Olinto. Moriró Cosí. (Florence: G. Venturini) -- Bonamici, E. Ad Espero! (Milan: F. Lucca -- Bimboni, Oreste. Prayer. (New York: Leighton & Co.) -- Borghen (?). Stornello popolare Toscano (sp?) (manuscript) -- Brogi, Renato, 1873-1924. Aubade. (Paris: E. Gallet); Romance. (Paris: E. Gallet); Les Trois Oiseaux. (Paris: E. Gallet); Mentre tu canti. (Perugia: G. Ceccherini & Co.); Volontario. (Florence: A. Forlivesi & C. c1915); Ne l' attesa d' amore (manuscript); L' ho amata tanto (manuscript); Romanza (manuscript); In riva al mare (manuscript); Ritrosa (Milan: Carisch & Jänichen c.1911); Prima notte (Florence: G. Ceccherini & C.) -- Buonamici, Giuseppe, 1846-1914. Ama.. sperá...credi.. e n' avanza! (Florence: C. Brattie & Co.) -- Carobbi, Carlo. O giovinetta pia. (Florence: G. Venturini) -- Chaminade, C#&233;cile, 1857-1944. Mélodies. (Paris: Enoch Frères & Costallat) -- Cohen, Maurice. Chansons orientales. (Paris: A.O' Kelly); Stelele. (Leipzig: Engelmann & Mühlberg) -- Rey Colaço, Alexandre, 1854-1928. Cante Flamenco. (Lisbon: Sassetti & Ca.); Trovas. (Leipzig: C. G. Röder); Cançao do berço. (Leipzig: C. G. Röder) -- Cordara, Carlo. Memorie. (Florence: Brizzi e Niccolai); Pater Noster della Tentazione di Gesù. (Florence: A. Forlivesi & C.) -- Corsi, Cesare. Stella. (Florence: G. Venturini); Carità. (Florence: G. Venturini); Stornelli e baci. (Florence: G. Venturini) -- Hardelot, Guy d', 1858-1936. All for you. (Cincinnati: John Church Co.c. 1899); Fermière. (Paris: Léon Grus): Say Yes! (London: A. Ascherberg & Co. c1895); Tristesse. (New York: G. Schirmer) -- Del Valle de Paz, Edgardo, 1861-1920. Notturno. (Florence: Nuova Musica c1900) -- Denza, Luigi. Occhi di fata. (Milan: G. Ricordi & Co.); Povera Rosa. (Milan: G. Ricordi & Co.) -- Seismit-Doda, A. Tempo passato perchè non ritorni! (manuscript); Just for my Sweetheart's Sake (New York: Theatrical Music Supply Co. c1904); You are the only one. (New York: The Harmony Music Co. c1906) -- Georges, Alexandre, 1850-1938. Chansons de Miarka. (Paris: Enoch & Cie) -- Graziani-Walter, Carlo. Preguiera di S. M. la Regina. (Florence: Al Mondo Musicale c1900) -- Keil, A. Lilia. (Paris: Choudens Père &Fils); Ressemblance. (Paris: Choudens Père &Fils) -- Lachaume, Aim#&233;. Cocorico. (Paris: Enoch & Cie. c1904); Un Baiser. (Paris: Enoch & Cie. c1903) -- Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Ruit Hora. (manuscript) -- Lèvi, Edgardo. In the moonlight. A Slumber Song. (London: G. Ricordi & Co.); Tua Stella! (Florence: G. Venturini); M' hanno detto in cielo i cherubini. (manuscript); Nuvole Vespertine. (Florence: G. Venturini); Signora Pia. (Florence: G. Venturini); Serenata di un moro. (Florence: G. Venturini) -- Litta, Paolo, 1871-1931. Morte di Cleopatra. (Vienna: Universal Edition A. G. c1914) -- Liuzzi, Fernando, 1884-1940. Di Notte. (Florence: A. Forlivesi & C. c1920); Tre piccoli canti popolari. (Florence: A. Forlivesi & C. c1922) -- Orsini, Giuseppe. Dear heart. (Parma: G. P. Orsini c1907) -- Oswald, Henry. Ofelia. (Florence: G. Venturini) -- Paolini, Paolo, 1941-. Chanson. (manuscript); Forse. (manuscript); Romanza. (manuscript); Tre Melodie. (Florence: G. Venturini) -- Perrone, Carlos. Invito. (Florence: A. Forlivesi & C. c.1908) -- Pignalosa, Luigi. Profumo! (Milan: Stabilimento Musicale Allessandro Pigna) -- Pizzi, Emilio, 1861-1940. Awake and heed. (manuscript) -- Post, Fred A. Chanson du Pêcheur. (Milan: Edition Ricordi); L' Hiver (London: B. Mocatta & Co.); Poète, prends ton luth (Paris: Léon Grus) -- Pratesi, Giuseppe. Quando. (Milan: Stabilimento Musicale F. Lucca) -- Quaranta, Francesco. L' ultimo canto di Akmet. (Milan: G. Ricordi) -- Rotoli, Augusto, 1847-1904. My bride shall be my flag. (Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.) -- Sarti, Alberto. Chaînes. (Lisbon: Lambertini) -- Sekiya, Toshiko, 1904-1941. Ombrello. (Tokyo: Tipikal Gakufu) -- Seppel ?, A. (illegible) Perchè partir. (manuscript) -- Sinigaglia, Leone, 1868-1944. Tre Romanze. (Milan: G. Ricordi & C. c1902) -- Sparapani, Senatore. Satana. (Florence: G. Venturini) -- Toselli, Enrico, 1883-1926. Cantate de Bettine. (Florence: Al Mondo Musicale c1900); L' Enfant. (Florence: Al Mondo Musicale c1900); A labbra bugiarde. (Florence: Al Mondo Musicale c1900); Primavera dell' Emigrato. (Florence: Narciso Baldini c1924) -- Thomas, J. R. (James Rodney). Beautiful Isle of the Sea. (New York: W.M.A. Pond & Co. c1893) -- Tosti, F. Paolo (Francesco Paolo), 1846-1916. Baciami! (Milan: G. Ricordi & C. c1911) -- Tr#&233;misot, Edouard. L' Auréole. (Paris: Enoch et Cie c1913) -- Vanni, Vincenzo. Non guardarmi così. (Milan: G. Ricordi & C.) -- Vannuccini, Luigi. Visione. (Milan: G. Ricordi & C.); Invito. (Milan: G. Ricordi & C.) -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Don Carlos. C'est mon jour (Milan: R. Stabilimento Musicale Ricordi) -- von Hammer, Marie. Gondolied. (New York: W.M.A. Pond & Co. c1895)
  - Songs dedicated to Mario Ancona, Bound, hard covers, green with leather spine and corners. 14 1/2" by 11" (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Bevignani, Enrico Modesto, 1841-1903. Two songs. (Cincinnati: The John Church Co. c1896) -- Bimboni, Alberto, 1882-1960. Primo album di liriche. (Florence: A. Forlivesi & C. c1911) -- Brogi, Renato, 1873-1924. Sei Melodie per Canto. (Florence: Bratti & Co.); Romanza. (Milan: G. Ricordi & C.) -- Cajani, Alberto. Campanaio. (Florence: A. Forlivesi & C.) -- Chaminade, C#&233;cile, 1857-1944. Ode to Bacchus. (London: Enoch & Sons c1899); Couplets Bachiques. (Paris: Enoch & Cie c1896); Espoir. (Paris: Enoch & Cie c1895) -- Denza, Luigi. Votre Voix. (Milan: G. Ricordi & C.); Rêve d' Amour. (Milan: G. Ricordi & C. c1898) -- Hardelot, Guy d', 1858-1936. Avec toi. (Paris: Léon Grus c1896) -- Lèvi, Edgardo. Sembrava un Angelo! (Florence: G. Venturini) -- Modona, Gino. Cavalcata di Mefistofele. (Florence: Nuova Musica c1903) -- Paolini, P. Chanson. (Florence: G. Ceccherini & Cie c1902) -- Tosti, F. Paolo (Francesco Paolo), 1846-1916. Greyswood. (Milan: G. Ricordi & C.); Mattinata. (London: G. Ricordi & Co. c1897); Zitta! (Milan: G. Ricordi & C.) -- Quaranta, Francesco, 1848-1897. È Morta! (Milan: G. Ricordi & C.); Morrò se il vuoi! (Milan: G. Ricordi & C.) -- Seismit-Doda, A. Tempo passato, perchè non ritorni? (New York: G. Schirmer c1908) -- Tirindelli, P. A. (Pier Adolfo), 1858-1937. Inno alla mia donna. (Triest: Carlo Schmidl c1901) -- Bimboni, Alberto, 1882-1960. Ricordo. (manuscript) -- Cordara, Carlo. Impressioni Giapponesi. (manuscript); A se stesso. (manuscript); Madrigale. (manuscript); Pioggia di stelle. C-- Modona, Gino. Cavalcata di Mefistofele. (manuscript) -- Pratesi, Giuseppe. Cornamusa. (manuscript)
- Sound Recordings
  - Selections, 2 3/4" by 4 1/14 broken (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Voi siete un po' tondo [?]; other selection illegible. 4301 (P.P) S.G.D. Pathé [?] 27258
  - Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Turandot. Tanto amore segreto, 1 3/4" by 4 1/14 broken (Box 17, Folder 2)
    B- 50 Thomas A. Edison
  - Ancona copies from Pathé discs, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, single-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Content of tape is the same as disc 9.3.1, sides 1 and 2.Tosti, Paolo, Sir, 1846-1916. Invano!; Malia; Chanson de ládieu --Hahn, Raynaldo, 1875-1947. Heure exquise -- Barthelemy. Serenamente -- Dannazione. Tra queste rose; Serenata -- Africana. All' erta marinar
  - Ancona copies from Pathé discs, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, single-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Content of tape is the same as disc 9.3.2, sides 3 and 4 with the exception of the omission of Cortigiani from Rigoletto.Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen. Chanson du tor#&233;ador -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata. Di Provenza il mar -- Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust. Ecoute-moi bien, Marguerite -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Era la notte -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser. O du mein holder Abendstern -- Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci. Prologo -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Ballo in maschera. Eri tu -- Additional Romanze unidentified
  - Ancona, Mario sings Romanze, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, single-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Two arias and one romanzaApril, 1958, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, single-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Tape made by Mr. W.R. MoranMozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni. Deh, vieni alla finestra -- Barthelemy. Serenamente -- Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Favorite. Pour tant d'amour
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Zauberflöte and Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Macbeth, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, single-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Metropolitan Opera and Chorus. Leinsdorf, Erich, 1912-1993, conductor
  - Pathé Records I, Transciprtion disc: 78 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Tosti, Paolo, Sir, 1846-1916. Invano!; Malia; Chanson de ládieu --Hahn, Raynaldo, 1875-1947. Heure exquise -- Barthelemy. Serenamente -- Dannazione. Tra queste rose; Serenata -- Africana. All' erta marinar
  - Pathé Records II, Transciprtion disc: 78 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto. Cortigiani, vil razza dannata -- Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen. Chanson du tor#&233;ador -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata. Di Provenza il mar -- Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust. Ecoute-moi bien, Marguerite -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Era la notte -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser. O du mein holder Abendstern -- Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci. Prologo -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Ballo in maschera. Eri tu
  - Pathé Records III, Transciprtion disc: 78 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore. Il balen del suo sorriso -- Rotoli. Mia Bandiera -- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni. Deh, vieni alla finestra -- Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Favorite. Vien Leonora.
  - Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Pêcheurs de perles. Au fond du temple saint, disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Pan American Record
  - Arias and Lieder, disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 11, Folder 5)